Mehrdad Qasemkhani

Senior DevOps Engineer

Asia/Tehran +3:30

Contact

Phone

+98 938 5200 818

Email

qasemkhani.mehrdad@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/gasemkhani-mehrdad

online-CV

https://mq.geekfa.net

Focus on

Cloud

Orchestration

Automation

CI/CD

НА

Languages

Persian English

Certifications

Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)

Summary

Software Engineer with over 7 years of experience in DevOps and full-stack development. Passionate about cloud-based technologies, DevOps culture, and tools, with a strong focus on Kubernetes orchestration. Automated build and deployment processes using GitLab CI/CD and Ansible, containerized applications using Docker, and orchestrated them with Kubernetes. Designed and developed RESTful APIs using Python, Flask, Neo4j, PostgreSQL, and Kong, with comprehensive unit and integration testing. Curious learner and excellent team player, seeking a challenging position as a software engineer or system designer, with aspirations to become a Chief Technology Officer.

Experience

Fanap Infrastructure

DevOps Engineer

May 2021 - Present (3 years 8 months)

Tehran, Iran

- Full automation of builds using GitLab CI & GitLab Runner.
- Fully automated deployments using Ansible.
- Fully provision services and Infrastructure as Code (IaC) using Ansible.
- Migrated CI pipelines from Atlassian Bamboo to GitLab CI.
- Docker containerization of applications.
- Nexus repository to store packages and Docker images.
- Produce and consume large volumes of messages using Kafka.
- Gather a large number of log messages using Promtail and push to Loki.
- Gather monitoring metrics using Prometheus agents (node-exporter, push gateway, etc.) to pull by Prometheus.
- · Visualize metrics and log messages in Grafana.
- Synchronize PostgreSQL databases using Bucardo in active/active mode.
- Load-balance HTTP (Layer 7) & TCP (Layer 4) traffic using HAProxy.
- Use Kubernetes as the container orchestration platform.
- Use Ingress to handle HTTP requests in the Kubernetes cluster.

Respina Networks & Beyond

1 year 11 months

DevOps Engineer

February 2020 - April 2021 (1 year 3 months)

Tehran Province, Iran

- Expertise in VoIP & Cloud Telecommunication Technologies.
- Developed Communications Platform as a Service (CPaaS) solutions.
- Proficient in Session Initiation Protocol (SIP).
- Configured and maintained Kamailio SIP-Server using the signaling section.
- Deployed and managed Asterisk & FreeSWITCH soft-switch platforms.
- Maintained Respina SIP-Trunk services and HostedPBX solutions.
- Implemented SIP & HTTP Load Balancing.
- Achieved High-Availability over SIP & HTTP protocols via VRRP.
- Dockerized services using Docker Compose.
- Automated the entire build process using GitLab CI (Continuous Integration).
- Persisted objects using MinIO object storage.

Backend Developer

June 2019 - February 2020 (9 months)

Tehran Province, Iran

- Developed Asterisk RESTful Interface (ARI) applications using Python and the Django framework.
- Developed Asterisk Call-App-Manager using pure Python over the Asterisk RESTful Interface (ARI).

Kara Tadbir Hooshmand Kish

Python Developer

September 2016 - May 2019 (2 years 9 months)

Tehran, Tehran Province, Iran

- Analyzed, designed, and developed RESTful API applications using Python,
 Flask, Neo4j, PostgreSQL, and Kong to serve subscribers.
- Developed comprehensive Unit-tests and Integration-tests.

Education

Shamsipour Technical and Vocational College

Associate's Degree, Copmuter (2009 - 2011)

Raja

Bachelor of Science (BS) · (2011 - 2013)